Yehia Abouseif

+1 (646) 689 2605

contact@yehiaabouseif.com

New York, NY

Yehia Abouseif is a multidisciplinary artist and designer, specializing in graphic design, digital product design and fine art, and is currently a senior at Parsons School of Design Influences include: Ed Ruscha, the colour red, Yorgos Lanthimos, and anything in between. Work can be viewed at **yehiaabouseif.com**

Skills

Adobe InDesign	Microsoft Office	HTML/CSS
Adobe Photoshop	InVison	JavaScript
Adobe Illustrator	Sketch	English (fluent)
Adobe After Effects	Procreate	Arabic (fluent)
Adobe Premiere	Responsive Web Design	French (beginner)

Experience

Communication Designer - The Shark Group

June 2019 - January 2020

Created several animations, including rebranding animations, social media posts, web design assets and a holiday card. UI/UX design for Daymond John's shopping page. Graphic design and branding work includes brand deck building, typographical and icongraphical decisions, building brand assets and creating mockups, for clients like Casa Zeta-Jones, Sorella and Fubu.

Graphic Designer - 1on1 Projects

October 2018 - December 2018

10n1 is a non-profit organization that elevate the narrative of Arab and Muslim Americans. With my colleagues, designed several articles into interactive and informative Instagram Stories to promote website launch. Created animations for Christmas and New Years social media posts.

Graphic Designer - Damian Loeb Inc

June 2018 - July 2018

Graphic design and studio intern for New York artist, Damian Loeb. Redesigned website, including recent works, archived works, past and current exhibition, press and a bio. Responsible for creating prints of art work, professionally printed on Edson Stylus Printer, which were sold or auctioned off for charity. Social Media planning responsibilities.

Graphic Designer – J. Walter Thompson

June 2017 - July 2017

Worked alongside the creative team, learning from established graphic designers, animators and conceptual thinkers. Designed brochures, posters and OOH adverts. Clients include: Ahli Bank of Kuwait, Commercial International Bank and Vodafone. Attended meetings with all teams, brainstorming design concepts and organizing future events, including the Gouna Film Festival.

Education

Parsons School of Design - Communication Design (BFA)

2016 - 2020

Dean's List, GPA: 3.75.

British International School, Cairo – International Baccalaureate

2008 - 2016

31 points. Visual Art, Information Technology in a Global Society, English, Arabic, Chemistry and Mathematics. Awarded the Visual Art Award by IBO for two consecutive years for academic excellence and creativity, the Duke of Edinburgh Award (Bronze, Silver and Gold), and the International Computer Driving License. Co-Head of Hopeful Youth Charity. Model United Nations delegate for 4 consecutive years.